A Guide to the Roy Clark Papers
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #10553-v
Roy Clark Papers 1935-1949
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
10553-v
ca. 200 items
American Rhododendron Society
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
These papers were given to the Library by the American Rhododendron Society through Kendon Stubbs of the University of Virginia Library on February 14, 1992.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of the papers of Roy Clark of Olympia, Washington, ca. 200 items, 1935-1949, a grower of azaleas, camellias, and rhododendrons, owner of Rainbow Gardens and a member of the American Rhododendron Society, containing correspondence, plant and seed catalogs, price lists, and plant orders from the early years of rhododendron growing in the United States. The material is arranged alphabetically by the name of the nursery or correspondent.
Container List
- Galle, Fred, 1947
- G. Ghose & Co., Darjeeling, India, 1947 & n.d.
- Goldsworth Old Nursery, Woking, Surrey, n.d.
- Green Pastures Gardens, Seattle, Washington, 1943 & n.d.
- Hillier & Sons, Winchester, England, 1942
- Homestead Nurseries, Boskoop, Holland, 1947-1948
- Ihrig, Herbert, 1939-1941
- Knap Hill Nursery Ltd., n.d.
- Layritz Nurseries, Victoria& Vancouver, British Columbia, 1942-1944
- Lem's Nursery, Seattle, Washington, 1942-1943
- Lindo Nursery, 1941-1946
- "Longview" Crichton, Alabama, 1940-1944
- Miscellaneous Correspondence & Printed including: H. T. Conner; Toichi Domoto, Charles O. Dexter, F. W. Schumacher, A. B. Lambert, and George Campbell, 1940-1947, n.d.
- Nearing, G.G., 1939-1941
- R. Gill & Son Himalayan Nurseries, Penryn, Cornwall, England
- R. Wallace & Co. Ltd. Trees and Shrubs
- Rainbow Gardens( Roy Clark), 1943-1949
- Royal Botanic Garden, 1943-1947
- Royal Horticultural Society, 1943-1947
- Semmes Nurseries(formerly Kiyono Nurseries), 1940-1946
- State Flower Nursery, 1944
- U. S. Department of Agriculture, 1935-1949
- W. Parker and Sons Nursery, 1946
- Wight Nurseries, 1940-1943